DIANA DISCHER

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Developer experienced with a wide variety of design tools and coding languages comfortable working anywhere in a full technology stack. Works independently or in teams to produce high-quality applications, utilizing a background in high traffic retail settings to understand prioritizing and effective teamwork.

WORK HISTORY

Framer, Web Content Manager, Designer, 07/2015 to Current Frameworks Studio & Gallery - Philadelphia, PA

- · Maintained and edited website content as well as front end site styling
- Generated email marketing campaigns for gallery events occurring 4-5 times a year
- Handled administrative communications from phone inquiries to work order/invoice generation
- Executed event cards from concept to print for gallery openings and announcements

Design Intern, 04/2020 to 04/2022 **ALMA Architecture -** Philadelphia, PA

- Managed internal databases and referenced manufacturer databases for architectural projects
- Conceptualized and executed digital and print promotional materials using a pre-existing design deck
- Facilitated a monthly meeting between the firm and manufacturers to enhance collaboration
- Surveyed sites and used photos and measurements to draft sketches in AutoCAD to be presented to clients and the zoning council
- Used Photoshop to render visual mockups, and completed pitch decks presented to clients

Soda Jerk, 10/2022 to 09/2023 Franklin Fountain - Philadelphia, PA

- Maintained efficiency as a front of house team in a high-traffic setting, catering to up to 500 customers in a night
- Offered a hospitable atmosphere while sharing insights about the shop's history
- Strengthened communication skills through interactions with coworkers and customers

Counter Staff, 07/2018 to 09/2022

Lil Pop Shop - Philadelphia, PA

- Interacted with patrons and offered recommendations from a seasonally rotating menu
- Maintained organization and tidiness of the shop, adhering to health and safety regulations
- Participated in staff meetings to discuss ways to improve efficiency and increase foot traffic

CONTACT

Address: Philadelphia, United States 19143

Phone: 2157967768

Email: dianamariedischer@gmail.com

PORTFOLIO AND GITHUB

- https://dianamariedischer.github.io/portfolio/
- https://github.com/dianamariedischer/

SKILLS

- Responsive to feedback, organized, team player
- Java, Javascript, Python, HTML, CSS, Czech
- · Git and terminal proficiency
- Team based GitHub deployment
- MongoDB, Mongoose, SQL, Sequelize
- RESTful APIs
- Node.js
- Bootstrap
- Figma, Adobe Creative Suite
- Responsive and accessible design

CERTIFICATIONS

Certificate in Full Stack Web Development from the University of Pennsylvania - to be completed in March 2024

EDUCATION

AutoCAD

Community College of Philadelphia - Philadelphia, PA

Candidate for Bachelor of Arts, Fine Art University of Pennsylvania - Philadelphia, PA

Studied Fine Art with a focus on design and color theory. Minor in Digital Media Design, gaining programming skills in Python and Java, along with foundational math concepts for computer science.

Game and Interactive Media Design Moore College of Art And Design -Philadelphia, PA